Leo Giesen, M.Sc.



| +4917683386614 | contact@leogiesen.de | Münster



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Customer-focused student consultant with half a decade of experience in working together as an effective team to achieve a common group goal. Strong programming skills developed over six years, such as Machine Learning. Track record comprises the development of a canteen recommender system integrating various data sources ensuring high quality recommendations and deep learning neural network to detect trees in satellite images. Supportive leader and committed team player dedicated to team and self-improvement.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Data Science (Machine Learning, Data Analytics)
- Project Management
- Modelling (BPMN 2.0, EPK, ArchiMate)
- Web development (Vue.js, API)

- Programming languages (Python, JavaScript, R, SQL, and Java)
- Microsoft Office (PowerPoint, Excel, Word, PowerBI, PowerAutomate, and PowerApps)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Chairman of the Board and Student Consultant | 03/2019 until today move - Studentische Unternehmensberatung e. V., Münster, Germany

Led the student initiative with over 125 active members. It is one of the leading student management consultancies. Board member of the departments HR, Quality Management, and IT. Active member of the IT-department.

- Led the association as Board Member for HR, Quality Management and IT for one year since August 2023
- Developed multiple websites and an eBusiness including online branding
- Restructured the IT architecture of a public transport company as project manager to ensure effective cross-company collaboration and improved internal digital workflows upon re-commissioning
- Supported the development of an internal strategy as controller
- Successfully organized numerous events, such as the candidate project in corporation with start-ups, socials, general assemblies, workshops, association meetings and congress visits
- Represented the association externally and prepared the audit
- Motivating students to participate freely and foster their development
- Solved multiple IT challenges, such as automations and IT infrastructure-related issues
- Completed and gave training courses and workshops about efficiently creating and giving presentations, project management, agile development, and business intelligence
- Developed great time management, planning, organization, communication, presentation, and analytical skills in real projects to ensure effective and goal-oriented teamwork under pressure

Working Student | 09/2022 - 08/2023

viadee AG, Münster, Germany

Found solutions and gained insights using Data Science in R&D at an IT management consultancy

- Improved target business process in Industry 4.0 with BPMN 2.0, Machine Learning, Data Analytics, Process Mining, and research
- Enhanced theoretical knowledge and implementation of Machine Learning models and Data Analysis

Software Developer | 10/2021 - 12/2021

zeb.information.technology GmbH & Co. KG, Münster, Germany

Developed for one of the leading strategy and management consultancies for the financial sector in Europe

- Increased the accuracy of a document classification machine learning model from 50% to 83% by implementing a Support Vector Machines approach
- Gained insights into Natural Language Processing

Leo Giesen, M.Sc.



| +4917683386614 | contact@leogiesen.de | Münster



Research Assistant | 03/2019 - 12/2023

Universität Münster | European Research Center for Information Systems, Münster, Germany

Made a crucial contribution to research at one of the top 200 universities worldwide

- Supported scientific research through methodical literature review and other scientific activities
- Developed the frontend of a fitness app using Vue.js

EDUCATION

Information Systems, M. Sc. | 04/2022 until today

University of Münster, Münster, Germany

Studying with a focus on business intelligence and business networks at the University of Münster, which is one of the world's 200 best universities

- Developed a canteen recommender system integrating various data sources ensuring high quality recommendations at a great performance
- Developed an algorithm with various machine learning models automating the document checks in the utilities industry in the market area conversion in Germany (image comparison, classification, object detection, semantic segmentation, perspective correction, optical character recognition)
- Implemented a regression model to determine the height of German forests in satellite images (CNN and traditional machine learning models)
- Implemented a location-based sentiment analysis (natural language processing)
- Designed and managed an enterprise architecture (TOGAF and ArchiMate)

Business Informatics, B. Sc. | 10/2018 - 03/2022

University of Münster, Münster, Germany

Focused on deep learning at the University of Münster, ranked among the world's top 200 universities

- Developed a deep learning neural network to detect trees in satellite images (semantic segmentation)
- Implemented a web-based simulation platform for public administrations. Lead the front-end development team of seven members
- Developed a land usage and land coverage machine learning model (semantic segmentation)
- Designed a data-driven digital business model using the business model canvas

Abitur | 07/2016 - 06/2018

Evangelisch Stiftisches Gymnasium, Gütersloh, Germany

- Elevated my English skills to a C1-level in bilingual classes and my English advanced course
- Spent a term at Cambridge International School in England, where I also developed the ability to quickly integrate and adapt myself into a new environment
- Advanced French language skills on a student exchange to Lyon
- Developed computer and Microsoft Office skills because of daily computer work and a fast-typing class

LANGUAGES

- German (native C2)
- English (business fluent C1)

- Spanish (conversational B1/B2)
- French (basic B1)